Yuan LYU

Master Internship

EDUCATION

Master of Science in Human Computer Interaction and Design

EIT Digital Master School Sep. 2015 ~ Sep. 2017 (expected)

University Paris-Sud, France Sep.2015 ~ Jun.2016
Technical University Berlin, Germany Oct.2016 ~ Sep.2017(expected)

Bachelor of Engineering in Network Engineering

Dalian Maritime University, China Sep.2011 ~ Jun.2015, GPA:82/100

EXPERIENCE

UI/UX Designer, Bingo for elders

Quality and Usability Project Oct.2016 ~ Present
In charge of UI Design and User test for this Android tablet game app.

Project Manager, Emotiv Quality Validation

Neuro-Usability Project Oct.2016 ~ Present

- · Idea generation
- · Setup test prototype and user test
- · Data analysis (expected)

APP Designer & Technical Support, Transmetics

Business Development Lab Course Sep. 2015 ~ Present

- · App design, idea generation
- · Android platform development
- · User test and Market analysis

UX Intern

Innovation Institute, FOTILE Kitchen Ware Co. Ltd. Oct. 2014 ~ Jan. 2015

- · Co-designed interface for new oven, steam box and microwave oven
- · Implement the high-fidelity Prototype
- · Made reasonable user test script, participated in user test

Research Assistant

Sino-European Usability Center (SEUC) Nov.2013 ~ Jun.2015

Research on Dining-out of Chinese Youth and Innovation Opportunities with NCR (National Cash Register) Corporation

Designed questionnaire, did user interviews and gathered feedbacks by following the UCD method

Research on Service Design of College Community Website

Analyzed requirements and competitive, made the interface model and did relevant programming

EXTRA ACTIVITIES

HCI Course of Prof.Gerrit van der Veer (VU University Amsterdam)

- Task Analysis and Interaction Design, Oct.2014
- · Research Methods and Techniques for HCI, Jun. 2014

Webmaster of Hiyouth Website

Inside website of student organization Sep.2013 ~ Jun.2014

+4915733262956

yuan.lyu@hotmail.com

m www.linkedin.com/in/yuanlyu

Berlin, Germany 10963

PROFILE

I am a Human Computer Interaction Design master student from China.

I adept at understanding and communicating the story that drives design of product with empathy, passion and commitment. Sincerely look forward to a Master internship in the area of Interaction Design and User Experience.

COMPETENCE

DESIGN

In-Depth Interview

Questionnaire

Conceptual Storyboarding

Mockups

Prototyping

Usability Testing

Photoshop/Sketch

Axture

PROGRAMMING

JAVA/C#

HTML/CSS

ASP.NET

SQL Server

JavaScript

Arduino

PHP

MySQL

LANGUAGE

Chinese: Native English: Fluent

INTEREST

Swimming | Bicycling

Sketch | Chinese calligraphy

Harmonica | Flute

Travel | Photography